There can be only one.
Highlander is a adventure, action, fantasy film directed by Russell Mulcahy.
He fought his first battle on the Scottish Highlands in 1536.
He will fight his greatest battle on the streets of New York City in 1986.
His name is Connor MacLeod.
He is immortal.
Connor 'The Highlander' MacLeod, played by Christopher Lambert.
Brenda J. Wyatt, played by Roxanne Hart.
Victor 'The Kurgan' Kruger, played by Clancy Brown.
Juan Sanchez Villa-Lobos Ramirez, played by Sean Connery.
Heather MacLeod, played by Beatie Edney.
Lieutenant Frank Moran, played by Alan North.
Highlander is a 1986 fantasy action-adventure film and the
first installment in the Highlander franchise.
It follows Connor MacLeod, a  Scottish Highlander who discovers he is immortal and, after
centuries of clandestine duels, confronts his ultimate rival in contemporary New York.
It stars Christopher Lambert as MacLeod and also features
Roxanne Hart, Clancy Brown, and Sean Connery.
It is directed by Russell Mulcahy from a screenplay by
Gregory Widen, Peter Bellwood, and Larry Ferguson.
Highlander was a commercial failure on its initial theatrical release, grossing only a little less than $13
million worldwide against a production budget of $19 million, while receiving mixed reviews.
Nevertheless, it became a cult film and inspired several
film sequels and television spin-offs.
British rock band Queen recorded several songs for the film's soundtrack, and those
songs also appeared on their 1986 studio album, A Kind of Magic.
Another Queen song, "Hammer to Fall", is also used in the film, although it
was recorded from the band's previous studio album, The Works.
One of the songs from A Kind of Magic, "Princes of the Universe", was
also used for the title sequence in the television series.
The tagline, "There can be only one", has carried on into pop culture.
The film explores themes of new york city, martial
arts, swordplay, immortality, scotland.
The tone is uplifting and dark and intense.